Did you know that using certain types of oil additives with synthetic lubricants or synthetic oils could actually be detrimental to your engine's performance?
Hi, my name is Jeff Jannett, I'm a Harley Davidson certified Master Technician and today we'll be discussing oil additives.
A lot of Technicians in the industry, I've been in the industry for ten years, we all believe, never met one that would disagree with me, that oil additives are not necessary, especially for air cooled V Twin motorcycles.
A lot of the programs that you see that tout their product, products that are actually manufactured, not going to name a lot of names, but they throw you out some great infomercials, yeah, great, lot of testimonials, and so forth.
But if you notice a lot of the test beds they're using are automobiles, trucks, diesels.
Air cooled V Twin motorcycles, if you follow the maintenance schedule, if you change your oil regularly, if you use a synthetic oil, you'll do just fine without any additional oil additives.
Air cooled VTwin motorcycles specifically in hot States, I would recommend running synthetic oils.
There's several on the market; Amsoil synthetic 20w50, Harley Davidson Syn3, V-Twin synthetic motor oil.
Most of these are all designed for the air cooled V Twin motorcycles.
Again, additives I would not recommend the additives on an air cooled V Twin motorcycle, for the simple fact that you can actually cause more damage and harm and in some cases, specifically with some brands, ie.
the Mobil 1 synthetic, they can say you can void the warranty on the motorcycle if you use an additive with a synthetic.
Again, my name is Jeff Jannett, Harley Davidson Master Technician, and if you have any further questions about Harley Davidson oil additives, feel free to browse the Web.
There are numerous articles on it and a lot of information out there.
But, any further questions talk to your local Tech.
They can be more than happy to help you.